<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
<channel>
<generator>http://textpattern.com/</generator>
<title>Maxvoltar</title>
<link>http://maxvoltar.com/</link>
<description />
<copyright>Copyrights (c) 2010 Maxvoltar. All rights reserved.</copyright>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 14:35:53 GMT</pubDate>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/maxvoltar" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" /><item>
<title>Dreaming of an Apple Tablet</title>
<description>&lt;p class="conversation"&gt;&lt;cite&gt;My Mom&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Have you heard, Apple&amp;#8217;s launching a pill in a couple of weeks!!&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Me&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Me&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Erm&amp;#8230;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Me&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Me&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Is it possible you mean a &amp;#8216;tablet&amp;#8217;?&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;My Mom&lt;/cite&gt;: &lt;q&gt;Yeah that!&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Audience&lt;/cite&gt;: [hysterical laughter]&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;The band&lt;/cite&gt;: [rimshot]&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;It looks like everyone and their next door neighbor is super excited about whatever Apple will supposable reveal on January 27th. We&amp;#8217;re no longer asking ourselves &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Will&lt;/em&gt; Apple launch a tablet,&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;When&lt;/em&gt; will the tablet be available?&amp;#8221; No, we&amp;#8217;re completely certain Apple will reveal a 10&amp;#8221; touchscreen pumped up iPhone/scaled down Mac in the upcoming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;The buzz around this is only comparable with the launch of the first generation iPhone. As far as I can tell, there&amp;#8217;ve always been 2 mayor subjects when it came to rumors about which products Apple could launch: A phone, and a tablet. Which makes me wonder what rumor sites will talk about after Steve pulls a tablet out of his pocket on January 27th. As &lt;cite&gt;Spencer Fry&lt;/cite&gt; said on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/spencerfry/status/7209665867"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;q&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll just go back to bitching about [the] Apple TV.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;I had a large draft with predictions ready, but waited too long to publish it. By the time I opened it early this week, multiple bloggers had already written a lot on the subject, and covered about 75% of my ideas. Here&amp;#8217;s a list you should check out if you want to catch up on what everyone is &lt;em&gt;guessing&lt;/em&gt; the tablet will be:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2009/12/the_tablet"&gt;John&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/2010/01/tablet_musings"&gt;Gruber&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.marco.org/310348919"&gt;Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/staff/fatbits/2010/01/antacid-tablet.ars"&gt;John Siracusa&lt;/a&gt; in an article for Ars Technica&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://aaronmahnke.com/2009/12/23/apples-tablet-device/"&gt;Aaron Mahnke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.suntimes.com/technology/ihnatko/1980077,ihnatko-apple-tablet-microsoft-010710.article"&gt;Andy Ihnatko&lt;/a&gt; in an article for the Chicago Sun-Times&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://twit.tv/mbw174"&gt;Leo Laporte, Alex Lindsay, Andy Ihnatko, and John Gruber&lt;/a&gt; discuss about the tablet for an hour on an episode of MacBreak Weekly&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mrgan.tumblr.com/post/318412000/diy"&gt;Neven&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://mrgan.tumblr.com/post/323938510/diy-pt-ii"&gt;Morgan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.loopinsight.com/2010/01/08/prediction-apple-to-release-two-tablets-and-other-prognostications/"&gt;Jim Dalrymple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;A couple of these much respected bloggers mention that Apple might try to change the way we see desktops and laptops. Combined with this new &lt;a href="http://www.uncrate.com/men/gear/laptops/lenovo-ideapad-u1-hybrid-notebook/"&gt;Lenovo IdeaPad U1 Hybrid Notebook&lt;/a&gt; (what&amp;#8217;s in a name&amp;#8230;), it sparked my imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h3&gt;I had a dream&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;What about this: You have a tablet, which stores all your media like music, pictures, movies, contacts, personal documents&amp;#8230; It has a touchscreen, wifi, bluetooth, fast &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSD&lt;/span&gt; storage and a lot more. Everything you can dream of in a tablet, a nice &amp;#8220;computer&amp;#8221; you could use on the couch, in bed, on the toilet, in the kitchen. Let&amp;#8217;s say it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p class="image alt"&gt;&lt;img src="http://maxvoltar.com/images/7.png" width="460" height="200" alt="The Tablet" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Exhibit A: The Tablet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Next, imagine an iMac sans the internal computer, just a screen with some extra storage, extra &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt;, a stronger video card, maybe even an extra processor, and a docking bay for the tablet. Sounds familiar? &lt;a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2008/01/03/apple-creating-imac-like-docking-station/"&gt;Yes it does.&lt;/a&gt; Combine this &amp;#8220;shell&amp;#8221; with our tablet, and you get a fully functional desktop computer:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p class="image alt"&gt;&lt;img src="http://maxvoltar.com/images/8.png" width="460" height="200" alt="The Desktop" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Exhibit B: The Desktop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Finally, to come back to our original source of inspiration, we have something that looks like the bottom part of a laptop. Built in you have a keyboard, a trackpad, some extra hardware and most importantly: A large second battery. If the battery life of the tablet would be something between 6 and 8 hours (in my opinion that&amp;#8217;s the minimum), this peripheral would extend that to 12-16.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p class="image alt"&gt;&lt;img src="http://maxvoltar.com/images/9.png" width="460" height="200" alt="The Laptop" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Exhibit C: The Laptop&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;This would be a perfect solution when you are traveling, when you need to take notes in a long meeting&amp;#8230; All your files, with you all the time, and no need to keep multiple devices in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p class="image alt"&gt;&lt;img src="http://maxvoltar.com/images/10.png" width="460" height="200" alt="The Complete Package" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Exhibit D: The Complete Package&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;m not an idiot. I&amp;#8217;m well aware Apple will never launch something that can slide or click into a peripheral. Too many loose parts that can break, too many separate &amp;#8220;devices&amp;#8221;. Like I said: a dream.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#8220;Why would I buy a device like that?&amp;#8221;&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Maybe you love using a laptop, but would like something more powerful for when you&amp;#8217;re in your office. Maybe you&amp;#8217;re a die-hard fan of desktops, but you mis having all your files with you when on the road. The possibilities are endless, especially when you add the option to install third party applications (like on the iPhone). &lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;#8217;s not running Mac OS X, but something more like the iPhone OS, it could be the perfect computer for your parents or grandparents. Or for your kids. Imagine the possibilities when using this device at schools. It could be a notebook, a diary, multiple textbooks&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t expect Apple to advertise the device as an electronic book reader though. Yes, it&amp;#8217;ll be used as one a lot, but it&amp;#8217;s not catchy enough to sell it under that name. Just like with the iPhone, the software independent developers are going to write for this device will reveal the true power of it. There&amp;#8217;s a lot you can do with a 10&amp;#8221; touchscreen device.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Nobody (not even the people who say they do) has any idea what Steve will pull out his sleeve on January 27th. Right now, it&amp;#8217;s a big blur, but as soon as the keynote is over, it&amp;#8217;ll be so clear, so logical, that we&amp;#8217;ll all say &amp;#8220;Now why didn&amp;#8217;t I think of that?!&amp;#8221; The only thing &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; know, is that I&amp;#8217;ll take 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Tags&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/apple/" rel="tag"&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/itablet/" rel="tag"&gt;itablet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/predictions/" rel="tag"&gt;predictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Short URL&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/21" title="Short URL"&gt;maxvoltar.com/21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/maxvoltar/~4/LiTfe027oEM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/maxvoltar/~3/LiTfe027oEM/dreaming-of-an-apple-tablet</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 15:09:33 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tim Van Damme</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maxvoltar.com/archive/dreaming-of-an-apple-tablet</guid>
<feedburner:origLink>http://maxvoltar.com/archive/dreaming-of-an-apple-tablet</feedburner:origLink></item><item>
<title>Siteseeing, week 1</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sightseeing? Siteseeing! Instead of posting links whenever I find them, I&amp;#8217;ll be posting weekly roundups, easily digestible, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;-reader friendly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;h3&gt;Project 52&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Biggest news this week is probable the launch of &lt;a href="http://project52.info/"&gt;Project 52&lt;/a&gt;. In short: By becoming a member of this site, you pledge to write at least one article per week. In a time where people only blog lists and instead use Twitter to spread their opinion, I&amp;#8217;m really happy this&amp;#8217;ll hopefully produce a lot of read-worthy articles! Looking forward filling up &lt;a href="http://www.instapaper.com/"&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; with some quality content. Some of my favorites so far:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sam Brown&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://sam.brown.tc/entry/414/how-to-stay-sane-when-freelancing-from-home"&gt;How to stay sane when freelancing from home&lt;/a&gt; has some great tips. I agree wholeheartedly, but in my opinion, if you&amp;#8217;re really serious about freelancing, you should look for a shared office. Probable my best investment ever.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Jason Cale&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://jasoncale.com/articles/1-degradable-interface-elements"&gt;The fine art of degradable interface elements&lt;/a&gt; is a school example of how you can make complicated forms that will work even if you disabled Javascript. And he&amp;#8217;s just plain funny.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always loved Matt Brett&amp;#8217;s writing style, and I&amp;#8217;m glad that in &lt;a href="http://mattbrett.com/2010/01/apple-has-ruined-me-for-everyone-else/"&gt;Apple has ruined me for everyone else&lt;/a&gt;, he&amp;#8217;s writing about something different than gaming.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;h3&gt;Others&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;One of the best conference speakers I ever saw must be Andy Budd. In &lt;a href="http://www.andybudd.com/archives/2010/01/7_ways_to_impro/"&gt;7 Ways to Improve your Public Speaking&lt;/a&gt;, he gives a lot of tips on how to become a better public speaker. Warning though: What he describes here is far from easy.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.drawar.com/articles/minimalism-is-mandatory/51/"&gt;Minimalism Is Mandatory&lt;/a&gt; tells about how content &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the design, and that minimalism is something different than just using few colors and graphics.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Tags&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/andybudd/" rel="tag"&gt;andybudd&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/apple/" rel="tag"&gt;apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/drawar/" rel="tag"&gt;drawar&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/freelancing/" rel="tag"&gt;freelancing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/frontendcoding/" rel="tag"&gt;frontendcoding&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/jasoncale/" rel="tag"&gt;jasoncale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/mattbrett/" rel="tag"&gt;mattbrett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/minimalism/" rel="tag"&gt;minimalism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/project52/" rel="tag"&gt;project52&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/sambrown/" rel="tag"&gt;sambrown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/speaking/" rel="tag"&gt;speaking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Short URL&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/20" title="Short URL"&gt;maxvoltar.com/20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/maxvoltar/~4/J7k-BGSnmWA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/maxvoltar/~3/J7k-BGSnmWA/siteseeing-week-1</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 13:40:34 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tim Van Damme</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maxvoltar.com/archive/siteseeing-week-1</guid>
<feedburner:origLink>http://maxvoltar.com/archive/siteseeing-week-1</feedburner:origLink></item><item>
<title>Stop being so fucking polite</title>
<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Carlin"&gt;George Carlin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/cite&gt; (May 12, 1937 &amp;#8211; June 22, 2008) said it best in his &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3_Nrp7cj_tM"&gt;Seven words you can never say on television&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Shit, Piss, Fuck, Cunt, Cocksucker, Motherfucker, Tits.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;#8217;ve been &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/1439172951?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=maxvoltar-21&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1439172951"&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B002CM6VDO?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=maxvoltar-21&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B002CM6VDO"&gt;watching&lt;/a&gt; too much of his work lately, but his arrogance and &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t care what you think or who you are&amp;#8221; mentality left me inspired, and opened my eyes: We are all too polite, and often forget what caring about something &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; means.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Let me explain: The web community is great. It&amp;#8217;s small, you know a lot of other people who do the same as you, and with whom you share interests. It&amp;#8217;s become really easy to quickly share interesting bits you found elsewhere on the net, or to spread the word on something you&amp;#8217;ve just launched.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;But we&amp;#8217;re just not critical enough. One person farts and the others start cheering about how good it smells. What ever happened to saying what you really think? I don&amp;#8217;t mean you should gossip, I&amp;#8217;m talking about saying what you mean, in public, or in private, to the person who&amp;#8217;s responsible for whatever you&amp;#8217;re criticizing. Tell them people start to notice they&amp;#8217;re re-using the same style for buttons in every project, tell them the line-height they&amp;#8217;ve chosen really makes for an unreadable blog.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;How do you expect people to believe you when you say something particular is worth checking out, if all you ever do is raving about how fucking awesome everything is? Good example of this is &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23ff+OR+%23followfriday"&gt;follow friday&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, you could blurb out 20 Twitter users per week you think people should follow. Or you could make a list of 50 Photoshop tips that&amp;#8217;ll make you a better designer. You could even make lists of the 1.000 most beautiful webdesigns of 2009. Instead, try this: explain people &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they should follow a certain person on Twitter, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you think it would be good for them to read an interesting tutorial, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you think that one website is beautifully designed, &lt;strong&gt;1 at a time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;But the person I&amp;#8217;m linking to always links to stuff I wrote/designed and he&amp;#8217;s a really good friend of mine.&lt;/q&gt; Hogwash. If something isn&amp;#8217;t worth sharing, don&amp;#8217;t share it. If someone isn&amp;#8217;t worth following on Twitter, don&amp;#8217;t follow him. No matter how much exposure that certain person has, or how good of a friend he is.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Quality content and design is becoming very sparse these days. Everything looks like a copy you&amp;#8217;ve already seen last week. How do you expect to see original, inspiring websites or articles when you never give decent feedback? It&amp;#8217;s like parents telling their kids everything they do is beautiful and amazing. After years of being told everything they do is holy, the kid will eventually think his farts smell like roses on a sunny morning.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Be honest, tell people what you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; think, and give constructive feedback. It can only make &lt;del&gt;the world&lt;/del&gt; &lt;ins&gt;the web&lt;/ins&gt; a better place.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Tags&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/georgecarlin/" rel="tag"&gt;georgecarlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/rant/" rel="tag"&gt;rant&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/tags/webcommunity/" rel="tag"&gt;webcommunity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Short URL&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href="http://maxvoltar.com/19" title="Short URL"&gt;maxvoltar.com/19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/maxvoltar/~4/-s7Yn3qlhco" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/maxvoltar/~3/-s7Yn3qlhco/stop-being-so-fucking-polite</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 15:34:28 GMT</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tim Van Damme</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maxvoltar.com/archive/stop-being-so-fucking-polite</guid>
<feedburner:origLink>http://maxvoltar.com/archive/stop-being-so-fucking-polite</feedburner:origLink></item>
</channel>
</rss>
